諜  報  風  雲
演員：菲力普西蒙霍夫曼 赫瑪永厄沙迪 妮娜霍斯  丹尼爾‧布爾
2001年穆罕默德•阿塔
在德國港口城市漢堡策劃了911恐怖攻擊
情報失誤和部門間內鬥使他和他的同夥
在未受察覺和干擾的情況下實施了襲擊
如今 德國和國際情報部門在漢堡保持高度戒備
決心不讓2001年悲劇再次發生
嗯
Yes.
我今天下午在機場接上了他
I picked him up from the airport this afternoon.
我知道
I know.
你知道我需要什麼吧？
You know what I need?
相信我 賈馬爾
你做的是正義之事
你們害怕嗎 我的朋友們
Are you afraid, my friends?
怕我們嗎
Of us?
怕伊斯蘭嗎
Of Islam?
穆斯林世界的人們在受苦
People are suffering throughout the Muslim world.
在巴勒斯坦 在阿富汗 在巴格達
In Palestine, Afghanistan, Baghdad.
但是，能用恐怖主義
But do I believe terrorism
為這些苦難作辯解嗎？
is the justifiable consequence of this suffering?
當然不能
No.
用暴力對待無辜人群 這不是真主之道
Violence against the innocent is not the way of Allah.
我在世界各地的慈善機構
My charities are set up around the world
為了消滅貧窮 也為了宣傳宗教寬容
to stamp out poverty, as well as promote religious tolerance
與理解
and understanding.
需要你們的慷慨解囊 來讓我們的工作繼續下去
We rely on your generous support to continue our work.
謝謝
Thank you.
馬克西
Yes, Maxi.
馬克西 有什麼情況
- Maxi? What have you got? - Yeah?
上午11點左右 警方接到報告
Around 11:00 a.m. police received a report
說中央火車站有一個形跡可疑之人
about a suspicious figure in the central train station.
警方收到了這張用手機拍的這張照片
They were sent this image taken from a mobile phone.
不是很清晰 但足以辨別身份
The quality's not great but good enough to make a match.
伊薩•卡爾波夫
Karpov, Issa.
車臣人 26歲
Chechen, 26.
被列為在逃的激進聖戰分子
Classified as an escaped militant jihadist.
可能有暴力傾向
- Hmm. - Potentially violent.
小心靠近
Approach with caution.
播放這一幅
Pull that down.
監控錄像拍到他在那一天
Security footage has him returning to the station
再次回到火車站
five times during the day.
我們知道此人身份嗎
Do we know that guy?
還不知道 正在查
Not yet. Working on it.
看手上動作
- Ah. Give me the hands. - Uh-huh.
是便條？
Some sort of note?
可能是鈔票
Currency maybe.
這是我們最後一次見到他
That's our last sight of him.
還有誰知道他來了
Who else knows he's out there?
警方還沒查出來
The cops haven't made a connection.
樓上的部門呢
Mmm. And upstairs?
估計也沒有
Mmm-mmm, doesn't look like it.
他們很快也會的
If not yet they will soon.
卡爾 拉希德 從各清真寺開始調查
Karl, Rasheed, start with the mosques,
收容所 不要打草驚蛇
homeless shelters, don't break anything.
尼基 去火車站找找看
Niki, try the railway station.
查出這個瘦小子是誰
Find out who the hell that scrawny bastard is.
很好
Great.
謝謝
Thank you.
伊薩•卡爾波夫
Issa Karpov.
穆斯林的名 俄國人的姓
A Muslim first name and a Russian last name.
這說明什麼
What does that tell us?
這小子令人困惑
That the boy is confused.
沒有父姓
And no patronymic.
他不是什麼人的兒子嗎
Is he the son of nobody?
伊薩…弄不好是耶穌
Issa... Jesus no less.
也許他是上帝之子 來拯救我們的
Maybe he's the son of God and he's come to save us.
拯救我
Save me.
安瓦爾 有什麼新鮮事
昆特 我的生活還是老樣子
要個肉夾餅
Doner plate.
黑咖啡
Coffee, black.
-一歐元  -謝謝
- One euro. - Cheers.
祝你安康
Salam.
謝謝
Thank you.
喂
Hello.
那個瘦小子 綽號海軍上將
That scrawny bastard, they call him the Admiral.
他常去希波紮克酒吧喝酒
He's drinking at Silbersack Bar.
你瞭解那酒吧吧？
- I think you know the place? - Ah.
非常瞭解
Better than I should.
我在看著阿布杜拉去迪拜行程的收據
I'm looking at the receipts from Abdullah's trip to Dubai.
從迪拜返回法蘭克福的途中
Why make a four hour layover, in Cyprus,
為何在塞浦路斯停留了四小時
on your way back from Dubai, to Frankfurt?
而沒有坐直飛的航班
When you can fly direct?
不知道 昆特 為了航空里程積分？
I don't know, Günther. Air miles?
運氣好的話 可能真沒別的
With my luck that's probably all it is.
"七個朋友"
Oh, "Seven Friends."
你只有這麼多朋友？
Is that all you have, Günther?
連七個都沒有
Oh, I wish.
這是一家總部在塞浦路斯的船運公司
It's a shipping company based in Cyprus.
好 我會查查
Okay, I'll check it.
好 再見
All right. Bye-bye.
海軍上將
Admiral.
丁克曼先生
Herr Dinkelmann.
失蹤人員
Missing persons.
奇怪的人
Strange boy.
緊張
Nervous.
他讓我幫他找個人
He asked me to find someone for him.
一個銀行家
A banker.
這個銀行家
And this banker,
他叫什麼名字
did he have a name?
不想要？
You don't want it?
布魯
Brue.
湯姆•布魯先生
Monsieur Tommy Brue.
布魯
Brue.
傳言說穆爾要有動作
Word is Mohr is on to something.
他的部下正在街上調查
His boys are hitting the streets.
昆特
Günther?
他們找到了卡爾波夫
They found Karpov.
好的
Ah, good.
不要管他
Keep him walking.
那個俄國人卡爾波夫是我們的人
Karpov, the Russian, he's ours.
那麼你們找到了他？
Am I to understand you've found him?
我要提醒你 你們在漢堡的權限
I remind you that your license to operate in Hamburg
要視你們和我的部門的合作而定
is contingent on your co-operation with my office.
我是在合作 迪特爾
I am co-operating, Dieter.
我希望這小子能去找別人讓他去找的人
I want this kid to talk to whoever he was told to talk to,
去被安排的地方禱告 去安排好的地方睡覺
pray wherever he was told to pray,sleep wherever he was told to sleep.
我不希望有誰在我們之前接近他
I don't want anybody else getting close to him before we do.
假如這小子引爆炸彈呢
And if this kid lets off a bomb?
那你就要負責了 昆特
It's in your hands, Günther.
幸虧這事不是你負責
Thank Christ it's not in yours
因為那樣的話 你就砸了
- because if it was you'd fuck it up. - Mmm-hmm.
那我要求你在書面文件上簽字
Then I want it in writing, your signature on the letter,
因為當炸彈在漢堡爆炸時
because when the bomb goes off in Hamburg
我希望你親自來看現場的鮮血
I want you there to see the blood on the streets.
你見過街上流血嗎
Have you ever seen blood on the streets?
小丑
Clown.
梅裡克有客人
Melik. We have a guest.
這位是伊薩 來自車臣
This is Issa, from Chechnya.
這位年輕人幫我把包提回家 他是上帝的禮物
我也做這種鬼臉
That's the kind of face I make.
婚禮
Weddings.
我每次參加婚禮 就看到又一個女人撞上南牆了
Every time I attend one, I see another good woman going to the wall.
那人家新郎呢
Well, what about the man?
新郎就是那南牆
The man is the wall.
哦
Oh.
這公寓的主人是萊拉•奧克塔
The apartment belongs to a Leyla Oktay.
土耳其公民 在德國定居
Turkish national, German resident.
是個寡婦
A widow.
有個兒子叫梅裡克
One son, Melik.
邁克爾的電話
Oh, Michael.
他們正在申請成為德國公民
They have a citizenship application pending.
邁克爾
Michael.
你得罪了穆爾
You've upset Dieter Mohr.
是嗎
Really?
這可能是因為
It probably has something to do
你任由恐怖分子在漢堡逍遙法外
with the terrorists you're allowing to walk the streets of Hamburg.
我們是為了盯梢
We're on a wait and see approach.
盯到什麼了
And what are we seeing?
還需要繼續盯梢下去
Enough to keep waiting.
別低估了穆爾
Don't underestimate Mohr.
他在柏林有很多熟人
He's got a lot of friends here in Berlin.
你把那車臣人交給他就是了
Why don't you give him the Chechen?
讓他出風頭 你專注于調查阿布杜拉就是了
Let him shine while you stay focused on Abdullah.
我認為他在把錢轉移到一家船運公司
I think he's moving the money to a shipping company.
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
還不能完全確定 但差不多
Not yet, but close.
我還需要一些時間
I need more time.
我會盡力的 昆特 但你也小心點
I'll do what I can, Günther, but watch your back.
據說美國人對此事也有興趣
Word is the Americans are taking an interest.
謝謝提醒
Thanks for the warning.
美國人
Americans.
昆特•巴克曼？
Günther Bachmann?
我是馬莎•蘇利文 美國駐柏林大使館的
Martha Sullivan. US Embassy, Berlin.
我當然早已知道你的名聲
I know you by reputation, of course.
肯定不是好名聲
That can't be good.
名聲好的人一般對我沒用
Men with good reputations usually aren't much use to me.
那麼女人呢
What about women?
這是我的同事伊娜•弗雷
This is my colleague Irna Frey.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
她會帆船 也做間諜
She sails and spies.
我不會帆船
I don't sail.
漢堡離柏林很遠
Hamburg's a long way from Berlin.
你來此何事
What are you doing here?
我只是旁觀者
Me? I am just an observer.
我被美國人旁觀過
I have been observed by Americans before.
結局一般都不好
It usually doesn't end well.
據我聽說 我們不是那種
From what I'm hearing, we're not the ones
你需要防範的人
you need to be worrying about.
各位早上好
Good morning, everyone.
穆爾先生編寫了一個報告
Herr Mohr has compiled a report.
我們經過調查確認
Our investigations confirm
伊薩•卡爾波夫
that Issa Karpov
是一個激進的車臣聖戰分子卡拉菲組織的成員
is a member of a militant Salafi group of Chechen jihadists.
今年早些時候 這一組織的頭目落網後
Karpov was arrested soon after the capture
卡爾波夫不久後也被捕
of the group's leader earlier this year.
這一情報的來源是哪裡
Where did this information come from?
我們在俄羅斯國家安全部門中有可靠的情報來源
We have excellent resources inside the Russian state security system.
經過24小時的審訊卡爾波夫承認
After 24 hours of questioning, Karpov confessed
參與了襲擊煤氣管道
to taking part in attacks on gas pipelines,
運輸部門、基礎設施、警察局
transport, infrastructure, police stations.
被俄國人審訊24小時
After 24 hours of Russian questioning
我們任何人都能承認任何罪名
any one of us would admit to anything.
你是在質疑這份報告？
Are you contesting this report?
不是 是的
No. Yes.
或許是
Maybe.
我們還沒看過這報告
We've not yet had the benefit of reading it.
這份報告認為 恐怖分子卡爾波夫來漢堡
The report concludes that the terrorist Karpov has come to Hamburg
試圖與本市的伊斯蘭小組取得聯繫
seeking to make contact with Islamist cells operating in the city.
他們就藏在我們中間
They hide among us.
-是嗎  -是的
- Really? - Yes.
卡爾波夫是個通緝犯
Karpov is a wanted man.
如果你知道他的下落
If you have knowledge of his whereabouts,
你就要按照憲法規定的正當法律程序
you are obliged to follow due process under the constitution.
你是說逮捕他？
You mean arresting him?
伊薩克•卡爾波夫的確在漢堡試圖取得聯繫
Issa Karpov is indeed seeking to make contact in Hamburg,
聯繫一個銀行家
with a banker.
你沒說過這事
We've had no briefing on this.
假如你調查仔細 根本不用我說
Well, if you were doing your job, you wouldn't need one.
我們不是警察
We're not policemen.
我們是間諜 伊薩•卡爾波夫可能對我們有用
We're spies. Issa Karpov may be of value to us.
我只要求再給一些時間
All I'm asking for is more time.
我們小組想在德國的伊斯蘭居民中
Our unit was set up to develop intelligence resources
發展線人
inside Germany's Islamic community.
-我們正是為此來漢堡  -哦
- That's why we're here. - Oh.
我以為你們來漢堡 是因為你們在貝魯特失敗了
And I thought you were here because you fucked up in Beirut
而你的朋友邁克爾•埃克斯羅完全不知道…
and your friend Michael Axelrod had no idea...
這個銀行家 我們知道卡爾波夫為何找他嗎
This banker, do we know what Karpov wants from him?
還不知道 假如我們現在抓捕他
Not yet and if we move against him now,
我們很可能永遠不會知道
the chances are we never will.
我認為他是有道理的 奧托
I think he knows what he's doing, Otto.
也許你該讓他繼續下去
Maybe you should let him get on with it.
限你72小時內
You have 72 hours to bring
把這事做個了斷
this matter to a resolution,
否則 我們就會了斷 不管你們是否合作
if not, we will, with or without your co-operation.
-好嗎  -好
- Okay? - Okay.
我們該去哪兒
Where should we go?
在街角那家飯店見面？
Meet at the place on the corner?
好
Okay.
你們先走一步吧
Uh, I'll catch up with you later.
好我們到那裡見
Okay, we'll see you there.
梅裡克
Melik?
我們有預約嗎
Did we have an appointment?
媽媽
這是安娜貝爾•裡克特
Annabel Richter, Mama.
你好 萊拉一向可好
Hello, Leyla. How are you?
歡迎光臨寒舍 安娜貝爾夫人
Welcome to our house, Frau Annabel.
很高興再次見到你
Nice to see you again.
請進請進
Come in. Come in please.
謝謝
Thank you.
這孩子是好人 安娜貝爾夫人 你知道嗎
The boy is good, Frau Annabel. Do you understand?
假如他做了什麼錯事 那是因為他不知道…
If he has done something wrong, it's because he had no...
你好 伊薩
Hello, Issa.
我叫安娜貝爾•裡克特
Uh, my name is Annabel Richter.
我是個律師
I am a lawyer.
我和一個叫"北方避難所"的組織合作
I work with an organization called Sanctuary North.
-請坐  -好
- Mmm, please? - Okay.
你來德國是尋求庇護嗎
Are you seeking asylum in Germany?
我去泡咖啡
I make coffee.
肯定是有原因的
There has to be a reason.
要麼你不能回你的祖國
Either you cannot return to your country of origin
因為那樣會有生命危險
because your life would be in danger
要麼你受到了迫害
or you have been tortured.
是的
Yes.
是哪個
Yes, what?
我受到了迫害
I have been tortured.
請原諒我 可這是我的職責
Forgive me, but this is my job.
我也希望相信你 可很多人都聲稱受到迫害
I want to believe you, but people make this claim all the time.
我必須…
I have to...
是誰傷了你
Who did this to you?
俄國警察
Roosskie.
你必須對我坦誠 我才能幫你
I cannot help you unless you are honest with me.
德國當局找上你是遲早的事
It's only a matter of time before the German authorities will find you.
最好是你主動找他們
It's better for your case if you go to them first.
-我們可以正式的…  -我決不回俄國
- We can make a formal... - I will never, never go back to Russia.
拜託
Please?
你聯繫這個人
You will contact this man.
他會幫助我
He will help me.
湯姆•布魯先生
Mr. Thomas Brue.
格裡戈裡•索維奇•卡爾波夫上校
Colonel Grigori Borisovich Karpov,
1986年駐紮於車臣
stationed in Chechnya, 1986.
他參與了集團犯罪
He was involved with organized crime.
重大犯罪 武器換毒品 販賣白人妓女
Big time. Drugs for arms. White slave traffic.
沒他沒幹過的壞事
You name it he was in to it.
卡爾波夫兩年前死亡
Karpov died two years ago.
-還有呢  -他有個兒子
- And? - He had a son.
伊萬
Ivan.
1986年生於車臣
Born, 1986 in Chechnya.
母親未知
Mother unknown.
好
Good.
裡克特小姐？
Fraulein Richter?
請跟我來
Please follow me.
請
Please.
"北方避難所"是什麼組織
What exactly is Sanctuary North?
我是個律師
I'm a lawyer.
我們的客戶都是離開了出生地的人
Our clients are people who have left their place of birth.
實際上失去了國籍的人
They are effectively stateless.
他們經常受過創傷
They are often traumatized.
你是什麼目的 裡克特小姐
What is it you want, Miss Richter?
要我捐款？
A donation?
對不起
I'm sorry.
那些話沒打動我
That was insensitive.
我是為了一個客戶而來
I'm here on behalf of a client.
他叫伊薩•卡爾波夫
His name is Issa Karpov.
你知道這個名字嗎
Is the name known to you?
卡爾波夫？
Karpov?
不知道
Mmm-mmm. No.
他有一封你父親寫給他的信
He is in possession of a letter written by your father to his.
信中提到"利比紮馬"
It makes reference to a Mr. Lipizzaner,
就是那種生下來是黑色 然後逐漸變成白色的西班牙馬
as in the Spanish horses which are born black but gradually turn white.
對
Yes.
你的銀行對這種業務應該很熟悉吧
This is a process I'm guessing your bank is familiar with?
信中有一個數字
The letter contains a number.
符合嗎
Does it fit?
符合什麼
Does it fit what?
這數字是這銀行中的一個賬戶嗎
Is the number an account reference in use at this bank?
我的銀行並不大肆宣傳我們的業務方式
I'm afraid my bank doesn't broadcast the manner in which it does its business.
這肯定很適合你的客戶們
I'm sure that suits your clients very well.
但假如這個數字的確屬￿本銀行的一個賬戶
But if this number does pertain to an account held at this bank,
也是很久以前開設的賬戶了
it would have been established quite some time ago.
我需要查一下記錄
I will need to check our records.
我查完後會聯繫你的
Once I have done so I will call you.
什麼時候
When?
我的客戶在漢堡的處境非常敏感 布魯先生
My client's situation in Hamburg is extremely sensitive Mr. Brue.
我相信
I'm sure.
他信任你
He trusts you.
從信的內容看 他父親也曾很信任你的父親
As, judging by the contents of the letter, his father trusted yours.
大傢伙
Big boy.
6…
Six...
3448？？？
格裡戈裡•鮑裡索維奇•卡爾波夫
"Grigori Borisovich Karpov."
對不起
Sorry.
沒關係 我已經戒煙了
That's all right. I've given up.
是嗎 只怕很難
Yeah? Good luck with that.
喂
Yes?
好
Okay.
"大西洋"
The Atlantic.
我會去的
I'll be there.
-晚上好  -晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
要喝什麼
Have something to drink?
一杯紅酒？
Uh, glass of wine?
純水
Uh, still water please.
純水 好的
Still water. Of course.
你常來"大西洋"嗎
You frequent the Atlantic?
呃…
Uh...
不常來？
Not your scene?
你說過你的客戶處境很敏感 所以很急
You said your client's situation was sensitive, hence the hurry.
我可以確認 你提供的參考數宇
I can confirm that the reference number you supplied
的確是屬￿"布魯兄弟銀行"的一個賬戶
does pertain to an account held at Brue Freres Bank.
那麼他想繼承這筆錢
Then he intends to make a claim.
那麼讓他帶個大皮箱
Then tell him to bring a large suitcase.
當然他需要證明白己的身份
Of course he will need to establish his identity.
我的客戶是在困難的情況下進入這個國家
My client entered the country in difficult circumstances.
那封信在他手上
He has the letter.
-我需要看看  -當然
- I will need to see it. - Of course.
另外他還需要提供一個器具
And in addition, he will need to provide a certain instrument.
什麼器具
Which is?
恐怕我不能說
I'm afraid I can't say,
但假如你的客戶是合法繼承人
but if your client is legitimate
他會知道我說的是什麼
he will know what I am talking about.
如果他有這器具呢
And if he has this instrument?
那就沒什麼障礙了
I see no difficulty in proceeding.
她要出來了
She's coming out.
很漂亮
Attractive.
不是我喜歡的類型
Not my type.
你喜歡什麼樣的 昆特
What is your type, Günther?
你這樣的 伊娜 你是知道的
You are, Irna. You know that.
去約翰內斯•勃拉姆斯廣場
Johannes-Brahms-Platz.
你好 湯姆
Hello, Tommy.
你是誰
And you are?
我叫巴克曼
My name is Bachmann.
領導一個反恐小組
I head an anti-terror unit
知道我們的人不多 喜歡我們的更少
not many people know about and even less like.
我們走走
Let's walk.
漢堡是世上最偉大的港口之一 湯姆
Hamburg is one of the great ports of the world, Tommy.
數百年來 它張開雙臂
For centuries it opened its arms
歡迎被沖上海岸的每一個外國人
to every foreigner who washed up on its shores.
而如今在911之後
Now, since 9/11,
每個深色皮膚的人
in the eyes of every dark-skinned man
我們都感覺這些人可能會殺害我們
we see someone who wants to kill us.
而且 確實有此可能
Problem is some of them do,
問題是 伊薩•卡爾波夫是不是這樣的人
but the question is whether Issa Karpov is one of them.
那個律師
The lawyer.
律師？
Lawyer?
安娜貝爾•裡克特
Annabel Richter.
你在酒店見過的律師  想和她上床的那個律師
The one you met at the hotel. The one you'd like to fuck.
怎麼 難道不是嗎
What? Not true?
你對她來說太老了 你我都太老了
You're too old for her, Tommy. We both are.
見到她 愛上她 但你永遠得不到她
See her, love her, but you'll never get her,
即使有那一筆
not even with all that black money
藏在你銀行金庫的黑錢
you've got tucked away in your bank vaults.
我只知道裡克特小姐代表的客戶
As far as I am aware, Miss Richter represents
在我的銀行裡有合法的金融業務
a client with a legitimate financial interest with my bank.
你的銀行與俄國人做生意吧
Your bank does business with the Russians, right?
以前是的 在我父親的時代
It did. In my father's time.
黑手黨？
Mafia?
主要是軍方的
Military mainly.
我完全可以
What's to stop me
對此置身事外
from just walking away from this?
不管是什麼渾水
Whatever this is.
要不要先全面審計一下你的帳目？
How about we start with a full audit of your books?
你父親並非只是個銀行家 湯姆
But your father wasn't just a banker, Tommy.
還從事洗錢
He was a laundryman.
你是在威脅我？
You're threatening me?
只是同情你
Just sympathizing.
留給你收拾殘局
You've been left to clean up the mess.
我們有工作要做 湯姆
We have a job to do, Tommy.
你要協助我們
You're going to help me do it.
到底做什麼
Do what exactly?
先從挽救安娜貝爾•裡克特開始
Save Annabel Richter, for a start.
為了什麼
From what?
為所有的事情
From all of it.
沒想到你會來
Hmm. I wasn't expecting you.
是嗎
No?
你以為誰會來
Who were you expecting?
今天不順心？
Bad day?
發生了一些意外
A few surprises.
享用你的威士忌 湯姆
Enjoy your scotch, Tommy.
上床時儘量別摔倒了
And try not to fall over on your way to bed.
伊薩 有人來找你
Issa, it is somebody for you.
-旱上好  -早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
謝謝你前來
Thank you for coming.
不客氣
Of course.
伊薩
Issa.
這位是布魯先生
This is Mr. Brue.
早上好
Morning.
你可以讓他看看信
Perhaps you could show him the letter.
親愛的卡爾波夫：
"My dear Karpov,
正如我們討論過的 請接收這封信
"as discussed, please accept this letter
做為一個朋友對另一個朋友的擔保
"as assurance from one friend to another,
假如你不幸去世
"that in the unfortunate circumstance of your death
我會很高興把你的兒子
"I should be pleased to acquaint your own dear son,
伊萬•格裡維奇•卡爾波夫
"Ivan Grigorevich Karpov,
介紹給我們的朋友"利比紮馬"
"with our friend Mr. Lipizzaner.
他只需要持有這封信
"He need only present this letter,
再帶上你的器具
"together with the necessary instrument
就可以了
"currently in your possession for me to act.
假如我去世了
"In case of my own death,
我兒子湯姆將履行我對你的承諾
"my son Thomas will fulfill my promise to you."
對不起 這是你父親的親筆簽名嗎
Forgive me. It's correct signature of your father?
是的
It is.
那我該稱呼你伊薩 還是伊萬
Should I address you then as Issa or Ivan?
伊薩
Issa.
這是我的穆斯林名字 也是我喜歡的
It's my Muslim name and I like.
但這不是你父親給你取的名字？
But not the one your father gave you?
我母親是車臣人
My mother was Chechen.
我希望在你的幫助下
I wish, sir, with your help,
能在漢堡體面的生活
to make an honorable life in Hamburg.
很好
Very good,
但首先 你明白需要有些證明
but first, you understand there are certain questions of fact.
我想問問那個物件
I bring your attention to the matter of the instrument.
我能不能問問 你是怎麼得到的？
May I ask how you came to be in possession of this?
是我父親的律師給我的
It was given to me by my father's lawyer.
那麼說來 是要求我
So it seems I am being asked
履行一個父親對另一個父親的承諾
to fulfill one father's promise to another.
是的 卡爾波夫是我父親
It's true. Karpov was my father.
你們並不親近？
You weren't close?
我父親殺過人
My father was a murderer.
他手上沾有車臣人的鮮血
He has Chechen blood on his hands.
而你似乎願意接受他的錢？
And yet you seem willing enough to take his money?
我聽說你是從土耳其來到這兒的
I understand you came here from Turkey,
是通過非正式的途徑 可以這麼說嗎
by an informal route, shall we say?
我能不能問問 你在土耳其是做什麼的
May I ask, what you were doing in Turkey?
我是在牢裡
I was in prison.
坐牢之前呢
And before that?
在俄國的牢裡
I was in prison in Russia.
-為什麼坐牢  -你不必回答這個問題 伊薩
- Why? - You don't need to answer that, Issa.
為什麼
Why not?
因為這與此無關的
Because it is immaterial.
和什麼無關 裡克特小姐
To what, Fraulein Richter?
你的客戶…
Your client...
他也是你的客戶 布魯先生
He's your client, too, Mr. Brue.
你的客戶要求繼承
Your client lays claim
他父親的賬戶
to his father's account,
可他沒有護照
yet he has no passport,
證明不了自己的身份
cannot prove his identity.
他有鑰匙 也有信 你還想要什麼
He has the key and the letter, what more do you want?
我們聽得不是很清楚 湯姆
We couldn't hear everything so well, Tommy.
賬戶裡有多少錢
So exactly how much are we talking about?
我不能告訴你
I can't tell you.
不能說具數額
Not exactly.
大致數額呢
A ballpark figure?
1萬？ 10萬？ 50萬？
數額
We're talking
在一千萬歐元以上
upwards of 10 million euro.
至少
At least.
-咖啡  -好
- Coffee. - Yes, sir.
-黑咖啡  -馬上就好
- Black. - Right away.
我本不確定你會來
I wasn't sure you'd come.
我想說明一點
I want to make one thing clear.
我不欠你任何人情
I don't owe you anything.
在貝魯特出了什麼事
What happened in Beirut?
你知道在貝魯特出了什麼事
You know what happened in Beirut.
我的聯絡網被毀了
My networks were blown.
那麼調到漢堡是處罰你？
So Hamburg is a punishment?
這要看你是否喜歡漢堡了
Depends on whether you like Hamburg.
或者這是你們的計策
Unless that's what you want people to think?
轉移別人對你的注意力
Take some of the heat off you so you can
你卻暗中進行調查
get on with the real game.
調查什麼
Which is?
費薩爾•阿布杜拉博士
Dr. Faisal Abdullah.
拜託 昆特 我們對他的瞭解 可能和你差不多
Come on, Günther, we probably know as much about him as you do.
你瞭解什麼 馬莎
What do you know, Martha?
我們知道你監視他幾個月了
We know you've been watching him for months,
也知道你受到壓力 需要儘快得出結果
and we know you're under pressure to get results.
我們知道他通過一個
And we know that the man moves money
穆斯林慈善機構來轉移資金
through a network of Muslim charities
每一次轉移 都會有一部分錢失蹤
and every time he does, some of it goes missing.
費薩爾•阿布杜拉博士正是那種
Dr. Faisal Abdullah is everything
我們最喜歡的穆斯林 而且他做的更好
we want him to be and a little bit more.
他寬容、開明 與西方國家交流
He's tolerant, enlightened, engaged with the West.
可每個好人身上 也都有不好的一面 不是嗎
But every good man has a little bit of bad, doesn't he?
在阿布杜拉身上
And in Abdullah's case,
這不好的一面
that little bit
或許就是殺心
just might kill you.
既然你們知道這麼多 他為什麼依然在漢堡自由自在
You know all that, how come he's still walking the streets of Hamburg
而不是被關在關塔那摩監獄裡？
and not rotting in some cell in Guantanamo?
因為我們只是懷疑但沒有證據
Because we think, we don't know.
失蹤的錢 我們不知道去了哪裡
The money leaves and we don't know where it goes.
況且在德國領土上 他還受到德國法律的保護
Anyways, on German soil he's got the protection of German law.
你們可從來不管德國法律
That hasn't stopped you before.
我們不再這麼做了
We don't do that anymore.
那麼是要求我們這麼做了
You want us to do it, then.
我不明白的是 你為何到現在也沒這麼做
I'm more interested in knowing why you haven't done it already?
請在這件事上與我們合作吧 昆特
Please work with us on this one, Günther.
我信不過你們
I don't trust you.
老習慣難改啊
Old habits die hard.
所以信不過你們
That's what I'm worried about.
我說的是你
I was talking about yours.
再見
Have a nice day.
我收到了你的短信
I got your text.
我…
I...
這事我不能幹下去了
I can't do this anymore.
會被人發現的 我能感覺到
Someone's going to find out. I can feel it.
我很害怕
I'm frightened.
他們盯上了我
They are looking at me.
他們都是
All of them.
我不幹了到此為止
I'm done. It's over.
我不是你的間諜 我是學生
I am not your spy. I am a student.
你無法逼我幹這個
You cannot make me do this.
我從未逼你幹過任何事 賈馬爾
I never made you do anything, Jamal.
也永遠不會
And I never will.
你是知道的
You know that.
我們第一次見面時
When we first met,
還記得我們說過什麼嗎
you remember what we talked about?
你記得嗎
You remember that?
家人  未來
Family, the future.
大多數人對此沒有選擇的權利 可是你有
Most of us don't get to choose, but you did.
你做出了正確的選擇
You made the right choice.
這條路並不容易
It's not easy.
但沒有回頭路
But there's no going back,
對我們來說都是
for any of us.
我們無法改變做過的事
We can't undo what's done.
看著我
Look at me.
來
Come here.
你是我的耳目 賈馬爾 我需要你
You're my ears, Jamal, and my eyes. I need you.
你對我很重要
You're important to me.
好嗎？
Good.
-喂  -湯姆
- Hello? - Tommy?
是我
Yes.
你需要滿足伊薩•卡爾波夫的要求
You need to give Issa Karpov what he wants.
呃 裡克特小姐？
Uh, Miss Richter?
我們能談談嗎
Can we talk?
或許我們一起喝杯茶？
Perhaps we could go for a tea?
你想怎樣
What do you want?
我重新考慮了你的客戶的情況
I've reconsidered your client's position.
我的銀行打算滿足他的要求
My bank is prepared to honor his claim.
你為何改變主意了
Why have you changed your mind?
或許是你說服了我
Perhaps you convinced me.
我以為你會高興的
I thought you'd be pleased.
好吧
Okay.
我會聯繫你的
I'll be in touch.
安娜貝爾
Annabel?
我們應該小心
We should take care.
我們所有人
All of us.
奉獻是我們的宗教義務
It is our religious obligation to give.
這是神聖的宗教稅
This is the holy practice of Zakat,
是伊斯蘭教五大支柱之一
one of the five pillars of Islam.
通過我們對這一慈善行為的堅持
Through our adherence to this practice of charity,
我們會更離上帝更近
we are drawn nearer to God.
昆特 那銀行家打來電話 他辦妥了
Günther, the banker called. He did it.
很好
Good.
伊薩 伊薩
Issa! Issa!
醒醒
Wake up.
你要帶他去哪兒
Where will you take him?
你還是不知道的好
It's better if you don't know.
我們必須走
We have to go.
你住在這裡不安全 不管是對你還是對他們
It's not safe to stay here. For you or for them.
這裡面有衣服
There are clothes in here.
也有一把剪刀和剃鬚刀
There's also some scissors and a razor.
伊薩 他們知道你的模樣
Issa, they know what you look like.
快 伊薩
Come on, Issa.
願真主保佑這房子
他們動身了
They're moving.
我們要去哪兒
Where are we going?
我哥哥弗洛林有個公寓正在裝修
My brother Florien has an apartment that's being renovated.
他已安排他們停工一周
He's arranged for them to stop work for a week.
下一站是哪兒
Where's the next station?
好
Okay.
我們下一站下車
We get out at the next stop.
我們要再找一輛出租車
We have to find another taxi, okay?
喂
Hey.
你擋住路了
You're blocking the street!
喂
Hey.
該死
Oh, fuck!
誰啊
Hello?
靠在牆上
Against the wall!
搜查別的房間
Check the other rooms!
住手
Ow! Stop!
臥室沒人
Bedroom clear.
我們快到了
We're nearly there.
我想和布魯先生談談
I wish to talk to Mr. Brue.
我今晚早些時候和他談過
I spoke with him earlier tonight.
伊薩 他說銀行會滿足你的要求
Issa, he says the bank will honor your claim.
我不想要那筆錢
I do not want the money.
什麼
What?
父親的錢是不乾淨的錢
Father's money is bad money.
可你除了這錢一無所有
But without it you have nothing.
我有上帝
I have God.
我給你帶了些吃的
I brought you some food.
裡面有個睡袋和幾件衣服
There's a sleeping bag and some more clothes.
我明天一早就回來
I'll be back first thing in the morning.
這裡不是監獄
It is not a prison.
這就是你最高檔的場所？
This was the best you could do, huh?
我是個穴居人
I am a cave dweller.
我會留給你一個有景觀的房間
I'll leave the rooms with a view to you.
你批准穆爾行動了？
You let Mohr off the leash?
他想激怒你的話 不需要我的批准
He doesn't need me to give him a reason to piss you off.
你跟丟了卡爾波夫 是不是
You've lost Karpov, haven't you?
我需要讓那個律師行動自由
I need the lawyer to move freely.
我可沒那麼大的影響力 昆特
I don't have that kind of influence, Günther.
你我都知道 你的影響力要多大就有多大
We both know you have all the influence you choose to have.
假如你要我繼續幫你 你就必須告訴我
Look, if you want me to help you on your way, you've got to tell me.
告訴我 你下一步的方向
Tell me which way you're heading.
上個月 一艘貨輪離開了塞浦路斯
Last month a cargo ship left Cyprus.
裝載了一千噸捐贈糧食駛往吉布提
It was carrying 1,000 tons of donated grain bound for Djibouti.
在也門南海岸停船加油
It stopped to re-fuel on the south coast of Yemen.
到達目的地後還剩下900噸
When it reached its destination there were 900 tons left.
在同一時間 有100噸糧食
At the same time 100 tons of grain
神秘的出現在也門的利伯維爾場
mysteriously hit the open market in the Yemen.
掙來的錢給了伊斯蘭激進分子
The money from its sale was used to buy rocket launchers
購買火箭發射器
for Islamist militants.
我認為這家船運公司是基地組織的一個幌子
I think the shipping company is an al-Qaeda front.
我認為阿布杜拉的慈善機構
I think that's where the missing funds
失蹤的資金就是去了那裡
from Abdullah's charities are going.
你是認為還是確定？
You think, or you know?
拜託 昆特 分享一下
Come on, Günther. Share.
阿布杜拉不是壞人
Abdullah's not the bad guy.
他是我們找到壞人的方式
He's our way to the bad guy.
他提供資金 購買武器來殺害美國人
A man supplies money that buys weapons that kills Americans
你卻說他是好人
and you're telling me he's a pal?
雖然他不像你們那樣賣力的
So maybe he's not waving the flag of freedom and democracy
揮舞自由民主的大旗
as enthusiastically as you'd like.
好了
Okay.
不用教訓我們了
- But he sees his people... - Spare the lecture.
他看到他的同族人一直受到不公平對待
He sees his people being fucked over from here to eternity.
這些話我都聽過了…
I've heard that before, so...
也許他有了一點報復的想法
Maybe a little bit of him wants to return the favor,
但也正是這一點讓他這麼有價值
but it's that little bit that makes him so valuable.
你說不是嗎
Don't you see?
我明白你的意思 可我們美國人不會這麼說
Okay. I understand. But that's not what my people would say.
你們美國人會怎麼說 除掉他 殺了他？
What would your people say? Take him out? Kill him?
然後你們會得到什麼呢
And then what have you got?
挖了個大坑 誰來填平呢
A great big fucking hole, and who's going to fill it?
沒人知道 尤其是你
Nobody knows. You least of all.
於是我們又開始查找
So we all start looking again,
在夜裡到處敲門
and tap-tapping around in the dark.
你想獨自調查阿布杜拉 對嗎
You want to own Abdullah, is that what you want?
以你的名聲和你這點人馬
A man with your reputation and your resources.
你怎麼能做到
How are you going to do that?
卡爾波夫的這筆錢
Karpov has access to money.
這或許會引起阿布杜拉的興趣
That may be of interest to Abdullah.
那律師呢
And the lawyer?
他信任她
He trusts her.
沒事的
It's okay.
沒事？
It's okay?
輕鬆
Dance.
-你是想在我面前逞英雄？  -不是
- Trying to impress me, Günther? - No.
聽著 我會再次約束穆爾
Listen, I'll put Mohr back on the leash,
但現在你欠我的人情了
but now you owe me.
嗨 安娜貝爾
Hey, Annabel.
很高興見到你 厄休拉還好嗎
Good to see you. How's Ursula?
不
No, no.
放開我
Let go. Let go of me!
喂
Yes?
好了嗎
Okay?
好了
- Yeah. Good. - Yeah.
拉希德
- Rasheed? - Mmm-hmm?
你不能這麼做 我是個律師
You can't do this. I'm a lawyer.
這是犯罪行為
This is criminal.
給我坐下
Sit the fuck down.
律師？
Lawyer?
你是恐怖分子的社會工作者
You're a fucking social worker for terrorists.
抽煙嗎
Cigarette?
對 你戒煙了
That's right, you've given up.
這就完了？
Is that it?
你就反抗這麼一兩下？
Is that all the fight you're going to give me?
和平主義者
Pacifist.
我們瞭解你
We know about you.
左翼律師
Left-wing lawyer.
家庭富裕
Wealthy family.
父親是法官
Father's a judge.
你做的每一件事都是對他無聲的反抗
Everything you do says "fuck you" to him.
你就這麼點能耐？
Is that the best you can do?
我可以走了嗎
Can I go now?
去哪兒
Go where?
回到你在"北方避難所"那些自以為是的朋友們那裡？
Back to your self-righteous friends at Sanctuary North?
可沒人會鋸掉他們的頭 不是嗎
But no one's going to saw off their heads, are they?
沒人會炸死他們的孩子
Nobody's going to blow up their kids
因為你在巴利島的海灘上
because you're on a beach in Bali
或是乘火車去在馬德裡或倫敦的學校
or riding a train to school in Madrid or London.
你怎麼敢這麼說
How fucking dare you?
How fucking dare me?
告訴我違反了所有法律
Tell me I've broken every rule in the book?
我踐踏了憲法的宗旨？
That I've trampled on the essence of the constitution?
你想說這套廢話嗎
You want to spout that crap?
是嗎
Yes?
你知道身在哪兒嗎
Do you know where you are?
你不知道
No, you don't.
這就是殘酷的現實世界 安娜貝爾
This is the real world, Annabel.
我們是在和一個叫伊斯蘭的國家中的激進分子作戰
We are fighting against the radical off cuts of a nation called Islam.
你已經越過了界
You've crossed the line.
你如今是站在他們一邊了
You're on their side now.
你好
Hello.
我不在乎你們打算怎麼對待我
I don't care what you do to me.
可關鍵不在於你 不是嗎
But you're not the one we're talking about, are you, dear?
伊薩 現在肯定很擔心
Issa must be worried sick.
不管你把他藏在哪裡
Wherever you've hidden him,
他恐怕在想你再也不會回去了
he's probably wondering if you're ever coming back.
但願他不會做出傻事來
I hope he doesn't do anything foolish.
來和我一起坐坐
Come, sit with me.
來
Come on.
現在有人想逮捕他
There are people out there who want to arrest him.
當然你知道這事
You know that of course.
我們擔心他們會在我們之前找到他
We're concerned that they will find him before we do.
他們和我們的做事方式可大不一樣
There is a difference between them and us.
他們想傷害他
They want to hurt him.
我們想幫助他
We want to help him.
安娜貝爾 我們不是你的敵人
You see, Annabel, we're not your enemy.
而是你的出路
We're your solution.
很好
Good.
你知道我的人怎麼對我說的嗎
You know what my guys told me?
當他們從街上抓走你的時候
When they pulled you off the street?
你沒有做出反抗
You didn't put up a fight.
沒像樣的反抗
Not really.
只是稍稍掙扎了一下
You struggled a bit.
喊了一下
Screamed a little, but
就任由他們抓走你
you let them take you.
似乎是你希望此事發生
It's almost as if you wanted it to happen.
你需要有人接管此事
You needed someone to take it out of your hands
因為你已經力所不及了 安娜貝爾
because you are out of your depth, Annabel.
你知道你救不了他
You know you can't save him,
至少靠你自己不行
not on your own.
你要麼求助我們
Your choice is between us
要麼找不到任何人
and nobody.
時間已不多了
The clock is ticking.
你知道他們會找到他 到時
You know they'll find him, and when they do,
會立刻讓他坐飛機回俄國
he'll be on the first plane back to Russia,
除非美國人想得到他
unless the Americans want him
然後我們就不知道把他關在哪兒了 他也不會知道
and then we won't know where he is and nor will he.
他不想要那筆錢
He doesn't want the money.
就是不想要
He just doesn't want it.
一半是激進分子 一半是
Half radical, half
有錢的年輕人
rich kid.
一半俄國人 一半車臣人
Half Russian, half Chechen.
愛他母親 恨他父親
Loves his mother, hates his father.
你我都清楚 伊薩•卡爾波夫並不知道自己想要什麼
You and I both know Issa Karpov has no idea what he wants.
還有一點
There is something else
是你我都知道的 是不是
you and I both know, don't we?
我們都知道他是無辜的
We both know he's innocent.
那麼你想幹什麼
So what do you want?
我想幫他
I want to help him.
伊薩
Issa?
伊薩 對不起
Issa, I'm sorry.
我做了個夢
I had a dream.
他們抓走了你 拷打你
They took you. They tortured you.
然後呢
And what happened?
我告訴他們你在哪兒了嗎
Did I tell them where you were?
沒有
No.
你比我堅強
You are stronger than I was.
你什麼都沒跟他們說
You tell them nothing.
去穿些暖和的衣服
Go and put on something warm.
我想帶你出去看看
I want to show you something outside.
好
Okay.
Right.
看看他
Look at him.
他很安全
He's safe.
這裡還有你的床
There's a bed for you here.
你最好別回家
It's better that you don't go home.
穆爾先生和他的人還在找你
Herr Mohr and his boys are still out looking for you.
你是想灌醉我嗎
Are you trying to get me drunk?
是的
Yes.
卡爾波夫怎麼樣了
How's Karpov?
快了
Getting there.
那律師呢
And the lawyer?
我已經幫你儘量爭取了時間
I already got you all the time I can get.
貝魯特的事兒是我們的錯
Beirut was our mistake.
我們的一個特工
One of our agents
毀了你的網絡 你分享了情報 是我們辦砸了
blew your network and I know you shared. We messed up.
只想告訴你這一點
Just thought you needed to know that.
我們經常犯類似錯誤
We make that kind of mistake.
我能理解你為什麼信不過我們
I can understand why you don't trust us.
你的特工和聯絡人暴露了
Your agents and contacts were compromised.
一些信任你的人死了
Men who trusted you died,
這會讓你永遠不能忘懷
and that stays with you always.
我們留下的
And all that damage
那些傷害
we leave behind.
那些生命
All those lives,
那些空蕩蕩的房子
all those empty rooms,
他們本來的命運是什麼
what would they have been for?
你問過自己這個問題嗎
You ever ask yourself that question?
我們為何幹這行
Why we do what we do?
有時也會問
Mmm-hmm, sometimes.
可每次都是同樣的答案
But I always come back to the same answer.
是什麼
And what is it?
為了讓世界更安全
Make the world a safer place.
這還不夠嗎
Isn't that enough?
動一下你的皇后
Move your queen.
雖然你是俄國人
Just because you're Russian,
不等於你下棋比我強
doesn't mean you're a better chess player than me.
我是車臣人
I'm Chechen.
好吧 你下棋厲害
Okay, so you're good at chess.
說說你別的方面
Tell me something else about yourself.
你說過你母親是車臣人？
You said your mother is Chechen?
她去世了
She's dead.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我父親強姦了她
My father raped her.
她死於我出生那一天
She died when I was born.
當時她15歲
She was 15.
這是我媽媽的
It was my mother's.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
你必須走
You must go.
你可以再刺激一下他
You can push him a bit more.
讓他動情緒
Try to get him emotional.
只要是自然而然的 你不妨發發脾氣
If it happens naturally, lose your temper.
可他不想要那筆錢
But he doesn't want the money.
我知道
I know.
可他喜歡你
But he wants you.
昆特
Günther?
你應該當心點
You should take care.
也許我們太心急了
Maybe we're pushing too hard.
你可別軟弱 伊娜
Don't go soft on me, Irna.
在這件事上容不得軟弱
There's no room for that on this one.
你哪件事上容許軟弱過？
Tell me one where there was.
早上好
Morning.
昨天有70人死於巴格達一處集市上
Seventy people died in a market in Baghdad yesterday.
上帝的意旨
Insha Allah.
"上帝的意旨"？
God's will?
還是妄以上帝的名義來殺人？
Or just a man who was arrogant enough to kill in his name?
她很厲害
She's good.
萊拉和梅裡克都被逮捕了
Leyla and Melik have been arrested.
他們可能會被驅逐出境
They may be deported,
就因為他們對你好
because they were kind to you,
因為他們把你請到家中
because they invited you in to their home.
跟我解釋一下 伊薩
Explain it to me, Issa!
上帝的意旨？
God's will?
你解釋一下 那個在巴格達
Explain to me why that man who killed
殺了那麼多婦女兒童的人
those women and children in Baghdad
和你父親的行徑又有什麼不同
is any different from your own father?
我來漢堡是為了開始新生活
I came to Hamburg to make a new life.
不 你來漢堡是為了找湯姆•布魯先生
No. You came to Hamburg to find Mr. Tommy Brue.
你來繼承你父親的錢
You came to claim your father's money.
我跟你說過 我不想要他的錢
I told you, I do not want his money.
原諒我
Forgive me.
或許
Maybe
有一個把過去拋在身後的辦法
there's a way to leave your past behind, Issa.
-拿著你父親的錢   -拿著你父親的錢
- Take your father's money... - Take your father's money,
-用它來做好事  -用它來做好事
- and turn it into something good. - ...and turn it into something good.
你的山羊被拴住了
Your goat is tethered.
只是一隻普通的筆
It's just an ordinary pen.
看起來像是筆 寫起字也像 聽起來也像筆
Looks like a pen, writes like a pen and listens like a pen.
拆開看依然是筆
Take it apart, it's still a pen.
你明白了嗎
Are you clear?
-明白啦  -嗯
- Are you clear? - Mmm-hmm.
你是代表一個富有的穆斯林客戶
You are acting on behalf of a wealthy Muslim client.
我們都談過了
We've been over this.
你是代表一個富有的穆斯林客戶
You are acting on behalf of a wealthy Muslim...
好幾次了
Several times.
他來這裡繼承一大筆錢
...who has come in to a considerable inheritance
而這筆錢的來路很可疑
and the source of the money is questionable.
他想按照宗教精神
He seeks to distribute these funds
捐獻出這筆錢
in a spiritually correct manner.
真是的
For Christ's sake!
我做這事不是為了你
I'm not doing this for you.
不管是為了什麼 湯姆
Whatever it takes, Tommy.
你好
Hello.
抬起胳膊
Put your arms up.
包
Bag?
嗨
Hi.
-嗨  -你好
- Hi. - Hello.
-布魯先生嗎  -是的
- Mr. Brue? - Yes.
-歡迎  -謝謝
- Welcome. - Thank you.
我是賈馬爾
I'm Jamal.
我父親在等你
My father is expecting you.
-你能脫了鞋嗎  -好的
- Can you take off your shoes? - Of course.
大衣交給我吧
I'll take care of the coat.
布魯先生
Mr. Brue.
-布魯先生  -幸會
- Mr. Brue. - An honor.
你見過我兒子賈馬爾了吧
You have met my son Jamal?
是的還有門外的一個人
Yes, and, uh, another at the door, I believe.
請坐
Please sit.
請
Please.
正像我跟你解釋過的
As explained to you,
我的客戶在德國的處境很敏感
my client's situation in Germany is delicate.
這是他捐贈的具體內容
These are the details of his offer.
你能看到上面有明確的要求
As you can see, there are specific requests
一部分錢要送到車臣
for some money to be sent to Chechnya.
醫院和學校
Hospitals and schools.
也許這是個惡作劇？
Perhaps this is a joke?
你加了個0來考驗我？
You have added a zero to test me.
數額是無誤的
The figure is correct.
這錢是哪裡來的
Where did this money come from?
他得到這筆錢
It has come to him
是出於繼承
in the form of an inheritance.
我的客戶認為這錢不乾淨
My client has come to regard it as unclean
希望在你的指導下散發出去
and seeks your guidance in disposing of it
以符合你們宗教的方式
in a manner befitting your religion.
你是個體面的人 我相信這一點
You're an honorable man, I believe that.
可你告訴我 我為何可以信任你
But tell me, why should I trust you?
我們當然必須信任對方
We must trust each other surely.
根據我的客戶的意思 我願意
I am willing, under my client's instruction,
把一大筆資金
to arrange for significant funds
轉帳給你
to be transferred to you.
你是個著名的宗教人士
You are known as a religious man.
受信任的人
A trusted man.
我相信你會把這筆錢
I accept you will direct this money
用於他希望的用途上
to the purpose he intends.
為何要這麼緊急呢
Why this urgency?
我的客戶在德國的法律地位並不安穩
My client's legal status in Germany is insecure.
我想建議你馬上接受這一禮物
I would recommend you accept this gift now,
因為他可能用不了多久
because he may not be in a position
就無權捐出這筆錢了
to offer it much longer.
明早我需要你開車送我去漢堡
-謝謝你 賈馬爾 -不客氣 父親
布魯先生
Mr. Brue.
-給  -謝謝
- Here. - Thanks.
博士 請這裡來
Doctor, this way, please.
阿布杜拉博士 我來介紹一下
Dr. Abdullah, may I introduce
捐助人伊薩•卡爾波夫
your benefactor, Issa Karpov,
和他的律師裡克特小姐
and his lawyer, Miss Richter.
我想和伊薩單獨談談
I wish to speak with Issa alone.
好的
Of course.
裡克特小姐
Miss Richter?
請告訴我
Please tell me,
你為何決定
why you have decided
捐出這麼多錢
to make this generous gift?
是被脅迫的嗎
Are you under duress?
沒有
No.
看著我
Look at me.
這是不乾淨的錢 先生
It is unclean money, sir.
是一個做了大壞事的人的錢
It belongs to a man who has done great evil.
我父親
My father.
我希望擺脫他
I wish to be free of him.
你做出這一捐贈
Whose sins do you renounce
是拋棄誰的罪過
by making this gift?
我父親的罪過
The sins of my father.
你自己的罪過呢
And your own sins?
我相信沒有上帝或者愛
I believe you feel lost,
你迷失了自己
without God or love.
你必須選擇真主的道路
You must choose the path of Allah.
只有那時你才能真正解除這一負擔
Only then will you be truly free of this burden.
布魯先生 我很滿意他的捐增是真心的
I am satisfied, Mr. Brue, that his offer is genuine.
很好
Wonderful.
這是一些慈善機構的列表 及其銀行信息
This is a list of charities, with their banking details,
以備你核實
for your verification.
請坐
Please.
看起來井然有序
It seems in order.
我會等待進一步指示
I will await further instruction.
邁克爾
Michael.
歡迎來到柏林
Welcome to Berlin.
都收到我的報告了？
Everyone got my report?
是的
Yes.
你需要專攻伯格多夫
You need to concentrate on Burgdorf,
內政部的
Ministry of the Interior.
是他最後拍板
The final decision will be his.
我將會需要卡爾波夫和那兩個土耳其人的護照
I'm going to need passports for Karpov and the Turks.
我們不做護照
We don't do passports.
他向那律師保證過了
He gave the lawyer his word.
是的 希望這次你們能把我的保證當回事
I did, and this time I want it to mean something.
在上面
It's up there.
我們查過了列表上的每個名字
We've checked every name on the charity list.
都是乾淨的
They're all clean.
巴克曼先生 請講
Herr Bachmann, please.
你們在看著我 看著我們
You're looking at me, at us,
可我們並不存在
but we don't exist,
不是合法部門 不是正式部門
not legally, not officially,
因為德國情報部門需要做一些
because German intelligence needs a job to be done
德國法律所不容許的事
that German law won't let it do,
因此我和我的人保持小規模
so me and my people we stay small.
保持在街面辦公
We stay on the streets.
應對各種困難
We make the weather.
不會有線人主動找我們 是我們找到他們
Our sources don't come to us, we find them.
成為他們的朋友
Uh, we become their friends.
他們的兄弟、父親
Their brothers, their fathers,
必要的話 成為他們的情人
their lovers, if we have to.
只有當他們成了我們的人
When they're ours, and only then,
我們才指引他們尋找更大的目標
we direct them at bigger targets.
需要一條小魚才能抓到一條鯊魚
It takes a minnow to catch a barracuda.
我這人並不釣魚 巴克曼先生
I don't fish, Herr Bachmann.
就是打個比方 艾哈特
It's a metaphor, Erhardt.
只是個比喻
Just a metaphor.
我們慢慢來
We take our time.
在一邊觀察 等待時機
We watch. We wait.
看看真主能給我們什麼
We see what Allah provides.
這次真主給我們的
Uh, well, this time Allah has provided
是伊薩•卡爾波夫和他的數百萬不義之財
Issa Karpov and his ill-gotten millions.
你們從我的團隊編寫的報告中可以看到
As you can see from the report my team has compiled,
阿布杜拉博士提供了他滿意的慈善機構列表
Dr. Abdullah has provided an extensive list of his favorite charities
做為這數百萬元的受捐贈者
to be the recipients of those millions.
每一個慈善機構都被中情局查過沒有問題
Each one of those charities has been CIA cleared.
我相信他會把列表上
It is my belief he will replace
其中一個名字替換成另一個
one of the names on this list with another.
"七個朋友"船運公司
Seven Friends Navigation Company.
你能給我們什麼證據
What kind of proof can you show us?
我們正在尋找證據
Proof is what we're looking for.
假如這個阿布杜拉…
If this Abdullah,
假如這條梭魚 如果我理解了這個比喻的話
if this barracuda, if I've understood the metaphor,
吞了這個魚餌
takes the bait,
你們以什麼來確保他的合作
with what leverage will you secure his cooperation?
負面的手段有
On the negative, uh,
威脅起訴他 坐牢
threat of prosecution, prison,
公開揭發 讓他的慈善機構名譽掃地
uh, public humiliation, discrediting of his charities,
把他的老婆孩子驅逐出境
um, deportation of his wife and children.
我選擇正面的手段
I choose the positive.
特赦 給他公民身份 他曾申請過十幾次了
Amnesty, citizenship, for which he has applied half a dozen times.
我們要給恐怖分子的資助者公民身份？
Now we are offering citizenship to financiers of terror?
你們都瞭解了行動計劃吧
You are all familiar with the operational plan?
我們有三個小時時間來逮捕阿布杜拉 讓他成為我們的人
We have three hours to apprehend Abdullah and make him ours
並且在任何人發覺之前就送他回去
and get him back home before anyone notices.
假如他不肯遵從呢
And if he does not comply?
那就把他交給你們
Then he's yours.
你們可以隨意處置他
Do with him whatever you need to do.
伊薩•卡爾波夫呢
And Issa Karpov?
他不能碰
He's to be left alone.
在我看來 這是不可接受的
In my eyes it's unacceptable.
找別人在鏡頭前應付一下就是了
Find someone else to parade before the cameras.
我們說好了
That was agreed.
必須保護他
He has our protection.
馬莎 美國方面是什麼意見
Martha, what is the American perspective?
也許你可以幫我們確定一下
Maybe if you could define for us
你認為長遠的目標是什麼
what you think the long-term objective would be.
我們要實現什麼
What are we trying to achieve?
讓世界更安全
To make the world a safer place.
這還不夠嗎
Isn't that enough?
布魯先生
Mr. Brue?
明早
Tomorrow morning.
謝謝你通知我
Thank you for letting me know.
你感覺如何
How are you feeling?
很好
Good.
你送他去銀行 然後你就消失
You drop him at the bank and then you disappear.
知道嗎
Do you understand?
你是逼我背叛自己的父親
You are forcing me to betray my own father.
這不是背叛他 是挽救他
You are not betraying him. You are saving him.
這種行為是愛
That is an act of love.
他已經被給予保護
He's been granted asylum.
我只能幫到這了
It was the best I could do.
我給了你伊薩
I gave you Issa.
伊薩給了你阿布杜拉
Issa gives you Abdullah.
下面會發生什麼
What's next?
你將怎麼處置他
What will you do to him?
阿布杜拉？
To Abdullah?
是的
Yes.
不會是壞事
Nothing bad.
我保證
I promise.
看
Look.
這是什麼意思
What does this mean?
意思是你可以留在德國了
It means you can stay.
我有東西給你
I have something for you.
辦完後我會給你打電話
-博士  -你好 布魯先生
- Doctor. - Hello, Mr. Brue.
這是確認資金的轉帳
This confirms the receipt of funds
從卡爾波夫先生
from Mr. Karpov
轉到我們在這裡開設的新賬戶
in to your new account we've set up here.
這些是你列出的慈善機構及其銀行信息
These are the charities you specified with their bank details.
每一筆轉帳都已經錄入我們的系統 只等確認了
Each of the transfers is logged in to our system and is ready to go.
噢
Oh.
請你再核對一下所有的賬戶信息
Would you please check all the details?
開戶人的姓名
The name of the account holders
轉給每一個受捐贈者的金額
and the money assigned to each recipient
然後你每一個都簽字批准
and then authorize each one with your signature.
我想替換一個
I would like to make a substitute.
我要改個賬戶名
I need to change a name.
"七個朋友"船運公司？
Seven Friends Navigation Company?
是的
Yes.
這是一家船運公司
It is a shipping company,
但其業務是慈善
but one whose business is charity.
我們得到世界各地的捐贈
We can have all the aid in the world
但也需要有船運給有需要的人才行
but it's worthless unless you can get it to the people who need it.
好的
Yes.
好
All right.
你的最後一個簽字
Your final signature.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
失陪了
Excuse me.
對不起 爸爸
堵車了
一點走不動
很遺憾我兒子堵車了
Unfortunately my son is delayed.
讓我們給你叫輛出租車吧
Allow us to call you a taxi.
-我要去了  -祝你好運
- I'm going in. - Good luck.
好
Right.
喂
Yes.
"布魯兄弟銀行"要一輛出租車
Taxi for Brue Freres.
很榮幸
A pleasure.
祝你安康
As-salam.
我去白沙島
My direction, Blankenese.
退後
Stay back!
等等
Wait.
住手 你們不懂嗎
Stop! What are you doing?
-等等  -不
- Wait. - No!
不
No.
伊薩
Issa!
-這是怎麼回事  -不
- What's going on? - No!
不
No!
起來
Stand up.
不
No!
伊薩 不
Issa, no!
住手 不
Stop it! No!
不 伊薩
No, Issa!
靠
Fuck!
導演：安東 寇班
編劇：安德魯 波沃爾